

ANNA WEINER

Data Analyst and Programmer

E: aw2838a@american.edu GitHub: annaweiner2838

PUBLICATIONS

Sommer, Rappel-Kroyzer, Adamcyzk, Lerner, and Weiner (2023). *The Political Ramifications of Judicial Institutions: Establishing a Link between Dobbs and Gender Disparities in the 2022 Midterms.* Socius, 9.

As a Research Assistant: Sommer, U., & Fassbender, F. (2024). Environmental Peacebuilding: Moving beyond resolving Violence-Ridden conflicts to sustaining peace. *World Development*. https://doi.org/https://doi.org/10.1016/j.worlddev.2024.106555

EDUCATION

American University

- MA Student at the School of International Service
- 4.0 GPA

San Francisco State University

- Graduated summa cum laude, 2022
- 3.93 GPA
- Economics B.A. concentration in Statistics

HIGHLIGHTS

Excels at analyzing diverse data sets, data munging, linear regressions, creating appealing visualizations, presenting complex data to non-academic audiences, and utilizing tidyverse in R.

Coauthored and/or researched several political science papers with Tel Aviv University. Research duties included data scraping, data cleaning, and presenting data to the research team.

EXPERIENCE

Potomac Strategy: Researcher JAN 2023 – PRESENT

Washington DC

- Conducts research and writes papers on Middle Eastern regional and international public safety concerns such as online extremism and people with disabilities.
- Duties include synthesizing large volumes of academic literature for non-academic audiences (including English second-language and individuals with learning disabilities), quickly developing proficiency in new subjects, and facilitating productive research with stakeholders and subject matter experts from across the globe on ground-breaking public safety topics.

American University: Teaching Assistant AUG 2023 – PRESENT

Washington, DC

- TA for advanced undergraduate macroeconomics course.
- Hosts office hours, grades assignments, and substitute teacher the class.

Moria Elementary and Tamar Center AUG 2022 – JULY 2023

Be'er Sheva, Israel

- Teaches in a low-income religious elementary school in Israel's periphery
- Also teaches English in an Arab Bedouin college preparatory non-profit, the Tamar Center

References available upon request.